<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Head of Security SOP

## Code Green

[bold]1.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry out arrests under the same conditions as their [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry a fully kitted security belt and a standard-issue sidearm (i.e., MK-58 or RG-2). They are also permitted to carry their Nanotrasen issued energy gun.

[bold]3.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as the [color=#cb0000]Warden[/color] for Armory equipment, portable flashers and deployable barriers;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Head of Security is [bold]not[/bold] permitted to collect equipment from the Armory to carry on their person;

[bold]5.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to either use their regular coat, or armored trench coat;

[bold]6.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to wear their unique gas mask;

[bold]7.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color] for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers;

[bold]8.[/bold] The Head of Security is encouraged to follow the [textlink="Security Rules of Conduct" link="RulesOfConduct"], as this sets a proper example for [color=#cb0000]Cadets[/color] and establishes good trust with the public.

## Code Blue

[bold]1.[/bold] All Guidelines carry over from Code Green. 

[bold]2.[/bold] In regard to guideline 5, leniency may be granted in order to ensure Command and other important members of the station are protected.

## Code Red

[bold]1.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, and 11 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to take whatever equipment they require from the Armory, provided they leave enough equipment for the rest of the [color=#cb0000]Security force;

</Document>
