<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
	# Lawyer SOP

	[bold]1.[/bold] Lawyers are to provide legal representation to any crew who requests it. They may not represent or speak on behalf of crew who have not retained them;

	[bold]2.[/bold] Lawyers are not to interfere with the processing of prisoners unless a prisoner has requested to retain them. If the collecting of contradictory evidence or testimony for a trial is necessary lawyers are encouraged to seek such evidence or testimony while their client is being processed or serving their sentence;

	[bold]3.[/bold] Lawyers are expected to keep information obtained in meetings from their clients in strict confidentiality. Should a client reveal information that would indicate they have intent to harm the station in a manner that would lead to an early evacuation lawyers are expected not to represent a client, but are still not permitted to reveal information divulged within a confidential interview;

	[bold]4.[/bold] Lawyers are encouraged to have a personal code of conduct, and to only represent clients in cases where this personal code of ethics will not be compromised. For this reason, lawyers may refuse to represent a client for any reason, unless ordered by the Magistrate to represent them. In the event that a lawyer has refused to represent a client, but is subsequently ordered to do so, lawyers are expected to represent the client fairly and not purposefully incriminate them or lose the trial in any way.

	## Lawyer OOC Rules and Expectaitons
	The purpose and spirit of the lawyer role is to provide meaningful role play through interactions with Space Law and SOP mechanics. This can be in the form of disputing punitive measures at a trial, or 'proving' the innocence of a convict. Lawyers can do this through any method they see fit, with the understanding that their role is meant to help other people have more fun - even if the other person has no chance of winning a trial or overturning a punitive measure.

	[bold]1.[/bold] Do not waste other players time. If something is frivolous you should make sure that there is legitimate interest in the role play from others, rather than pursuing it for the sake of your own personal bit or storyline.


</Document>
